Guide to the Edward Vitale violin music collection, ca. 1700-1900
George Mason University Libraries
- An electronic box inventory is unavailable. Please contact speccoll@gmu.edu for more information.
  - Fritz Kreisler Freie Bearbeitugen alterer werke der violin-litteratur ausgabe fur violine mit pianoforte-begleitung Niccolo Paganini Op. 8 Le Streghe (Danse des Sorcieres, Hexentanze), 1905 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Two arrangements for violin and piano by Maud Powell, Frederic Chopin Op. 64 No. 1 waltz, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Masterpieces for violin and piano, Chopin Op. 9 No. 2 Notturno (Wilhelj), 1899 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Carl Fischer Edition Compositions for violin and piano select pieces embracing the higher positions series 4 Goens Op. 12 No. 1 Romance saus paroles, 1899 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 84 C. Saint-Saens Op. 28 Introduction and Rondo Capriccioso for Violin and Piano, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - August Wilhelmj Bear beitungen und Compostionen fur Violine Gluck-Sgambati melodie, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Ausdem 18 Jahrfjundert Bearbeitungen fur Violine und Pianoforte von L. Lieberson Fingersatze und Stricharten von Efrem Zimbalist No 4 (Rameau) les tendres plaintes, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Original Compositions and Arrangements for Violin with Piano Accompaniment Third Series Souvenir Fraz DrLa, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - C. Fischer's Edition The Concert Violinist Choice Collection of Favorite Compositions for Violin and Piano #62 Adagio religioso - L. de Saint Lubin, 1899 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano No. 6 Hungarian Dance (Brahms) (Joachim), 1899 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Musical Classics from the Seventeenth and Eighteenth Centuries for the Violin and Piano Sarabande and Tambourin Jean Marie Leclair, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Mischa Elman Succes Classiques pour Violon et Piano Giardini - Gigue, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Arioso von G. F. Hundel Arrangements von J. Hellmesberger und L. A. Zellner No. 3 Fur Violine mit Clavier, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Perpetuum mobile fur Violine (No 22 aus den Studien Op. 1) mit Begleitung des Pianoforte von Henry Schradieck, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Willy Burmester Alte Weisen (Old Airs) for Violin and Piano Mozart - Deutscher Tanz, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - August Wilhelmj Bearbeitungen und Compositionen fur Violine mit Klavier Schubert 2 Lieder (Ave Marie - Am Meer), Undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and edited for Violin and Piano #25 Handel Prelude, 1907 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Mischa Elman Succes Classiques pour Violon et Piano A. D'Au Vergne Allegro Appassionata, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Suiten fur Violine mit Pianofortebegleitung von Franz Ries No 3 Op 34 Adagio, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Mischa Elman Succes Classiques pour Violon et Piano No 12 Rousseau Deux Menuets, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Sammlung Classischer Stucke aus Werken beruhmter Meister Fur das Violonrell mit Begleitung des Pianoforte No 4 Loure von Joh. Seb. Bach, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - A Monsieur Perrot Rondino No. 2 des trois Morreaur de Salon pour Violon avec Piano composes par H. Vieuxtemps Op 32 No 2 No 7781 (2), undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Geo H. Keopping Humoreske for Violin with accompaniment of Piano, 1899 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Souvenir De San Sebastian A L' Espagnole for Violin and Piano Christiaan Kriens, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Ecole Leonard Romance pour Violon seul oupour Violon avec Accompagnement de Piano Compose et Dediee a Mademoiselle Felicie Dodemont par H. Leonard, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Serenade tiree de Ballet Les Millions d'Arlequin de Richard Drigo transcrite pour Violon avec accompagnement de Piano par Leopold Auer, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Concert and Exhibition pieces for Violin and Piano Tivadar Nachez Op. 14 Danses Tziganes (Gypsy Dances) No 2, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Neue Klassische Albumblatter ausgewahlt und bearbeitet Violine oder Violoncell und Klavier von Emil Kross #21 Bach. Mein glaubiges Herz frohlocke, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Madama Butterfly Di G. Puccini 110065 Mandolino (o Violino) e Pianoforte, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and Edited for Violin and Piano #1 C. Ph. E. Bach la Complaisante, 1904 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Aus dem 18 Jahrfjundert Bearbeitungen fur Violine und Pianoforte von S. Lieberson Fingersatze und Stricharten von Efrem Zimbalist No. 3 Grazioli G. B. (1755-1820) Adagio, 1914 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and edited for Piano and Violin #8 Handel Arioso, 1906 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - From Mischa Elman's Arogramme Selected Works of Famous Composers for Violin and Piano Ludwig van Beethoven Menuet No. 2 in G, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Aus dem 18. Jahrfjundert Bearbeiturgen fur Violine und Pianoforte von L. Lieberson No. 1 Bach, Phil. Em. (1714-1788) Andante cantabile, 1914 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Transcriptions for Violin and Piano by Mischa Elman 2. F. Schubert wiegenlied (Cradle Song), 1911 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Transcriptions for Violin and Piano by Mischa Elman 1. F. Schubert Standchen (Serenade), 1910 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - C. Fischer's Edition Compositions for Violin and Piano Polonaise de Concert Op. 153 C. Bohm, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Edition Adolphe Grunwald A Monsieur L. Auer Serenade Melancolique pour le violon avec Accompagnement de Piano ou d'orchestre composee par P. Tschaikowsky Op. 26 Pour Violon et Piano Pr. 2 MK, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Bouquet americain Melodies populaires transcrit pour le Violon avec Piano par H. Vieuxtemps Op 33 No. 2 St. Patrick's Day, 1866 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Hommage a Rubini J. Artot Op: 8, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Serenta aus Opus 15 von Moritz Moszkowski C. Fur Piano und Violine Arrangement von Fabian Rehfeld, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - C. Fischer's Edition Compositions for Violin and Piano Serenite H. Vieuxtemps, 1903 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Brollops Schwedischer Hochzeits-Marsch Bauern-Tanz componirt von Aug. Soderman fur Piano und Violine Arrang. V. Theob. Rehbaum, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Album Classischer Stucke fur die Violine mit Begleitung des Pianoforte oder Orgel oder Harmonium No. 7 Buch Joh. Seb. Sarabande fur die Violine mit Begleitung des Pianoforte oder Orgel oder Marmonium arrangirt von Wilh. Fitzenhagen und C. Rundnagel, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - The Violinist's Portfolio of Modern Gems with Pianoforte Accompaniment Spinning Song Eberhardt Op. 98 No. 4, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Austrian folk songs transcribed for violin with piano accompaniment by Fritz Kreisler Viennese Popular Song, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Fritz Kreisler transcriptions for Violin and Piano Serendade Espagnole (Spanish Serenade) by Cecile Chaminade, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Compositions for Violin and Piano Select pieces embracing the higher positions Series 2 Hone, J Sweet Spirit Hear My Prayer from Wallace's Opera "Lurline", 1897 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Carl Fischer's Edition Compositions for Violin and Piano Select pieces embracing the higher positions Series 3 Rehfeld, F. Op. 58 No. 1 Spanish Dance, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Transcriptions for Violin and Pianoforte by F. Rehfeld L. Cherubini, Larghetto in B Flat, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Favorite Recital Colos for the Violin with Piano Accompaniment Series 3 Anton Rubinstein Melody in F together with Romance, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - From Mischa Elman's Programme Selected Works in famous Composers for Violin and Piano Ludwig Van Beethoven Menuet No. 2 in G, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Eight Transcriptions for Violin with Piano Accompaniment by A. Walter Kramer 8. Robert Franz Stille Sicherheit, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Eight Transcriptions for Violin with Piano Accompaniment by A Walter Kramer #5 Claude Debussy Evening (Beau Soir), 1915 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and Edited for Violin and Piano 24 Gluck Menuett, 1907 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and Edited for Violin and Piano #17 Mattheson Air on the G-String, 1906 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Humereske von Anton Dvoyak Op. 101 No. 7 e Fur Pianoforte and Violine von Fritz Kreisler, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Arioso von G. F. Handel Arrangements von J. Hellmesberger und L. A. Zellner No. 3 Fur Violine mit Clavier, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and Edited for Violin and Piano 1. C. Ph. E. Bach La Complaisante, 1904 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Drawing Room Pieces for Violin and Piano The Alpine Maid's Sunday (Saeterjentens Sondag) Melody by Old Bull Harmonized and Arranged by Johann Svedson First Series, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Selected Gems From the Best Composers Described, Annontated, Analyzed, Phrased, Fingered by Chas. W. Landon. Bach, J. S. My Heart is ever Faithful, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - A Son Ami Eugene Ysaye Farfalla (Will-o-the-Wisp) Caprice pous Violon avec Orchestre par Emile Lauret, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Willy Burmester Alte Weisen fur Violine mit Klavierbegleitung Schubert, Moment Musical No. 3, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Sarasate freundschaftlich zugeeignet Variationen fur Violine mit Orchesterbegleitung von Joseph Joachim, undated (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Lindenrauschen Abendglocken Ballade Drei Stucke Fur Violine und Pianoforte compouirt und Fraulein Gisela von Arnim gewidmet von Joseph Joachim Op. 5, undated (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Recital Music Friedrich Smetana Aus Der Heimat (Songs of Home) No. 1, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Austrian Folk Songs Transcribed for Violin with Piano Accompaniment by Fritz Kreisler Viennese Melody Gaertner-Kreisler, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Louis Couperin Chanson Louis XIII and Pavane, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Masterpieces (In Modernized Arrangements) for Violin and Piano 12. Niccolo Paganini Caprice No. 13, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Fritz Kreisler Compositions for Violin and Piano 3. Tambourin Chinois, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Dvorak Kreisler 2. Slavonic Fantasie, B minor SlavischeFantasie, H Moll, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Alt Weiner Tranweisen No. 3 Schon Rosmarin Violin and Piano, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 17. Friedemann Bach Grave, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Dvorak Kreisler 5. Slavonic Dances G Major No. 3 Slavische Tanzweisen G Dur No. 3, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Dvorak Kreisler 3. Slavonic Dances G minor No. 1 Slavische Tanzweisen G. Moll No. 1, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Masterpieces (In Modernized Arrangements) for Violin and Piano 17. Henri Wieniawski, Caprice in E flat major, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Masterpieces (In Modernized Arrangements) For Violins and Piano 13. Niccolo Paganini Caprice No. 20, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Fritz Kreisler Compositions for Violin and Piano 1. Romance, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Humoreske von Anton Dvorak Op. 101 No. 7 f. Fur Pianoforte und Vioine von Fritz Kreisler, 1906 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano Padre Martini Audantino, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano Alt-Wiener-Tansweisen: No. 1 Liebesfreud, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Masterpieces (In Modernized Arrangements) 10. Carl Maria von Weber, Larghetto, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - 6 Airs Varies for the Violin with Piano Accompaniment by Charles Dancla Op. 118 Second Series No 1-6 (2 Copies), 1889 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Klassische und Morderne Stucke fur Pianoforte und Violine Chopin, Nocturne Op. 27 No. 2, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - A Joseph Debroux Introduction et Caprice-Jota pour Violon avec Accompagnement d'Orchestre ou Piano par Pablode Sarsate Op. 41, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - A Madame de Lassabathie Reverie pour Violon avec Accompagnement de Piano par Sarasate Op. 4, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Fritz Kreisler Violin Compositions 17 Friedmann Bach Grave Arrangements, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Dvorak Kreisler 4. Slavonic Dances E Minor No. 2 Slavische Tanzweisen E Moll No. 2, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Masterpieces (In Modernized Arrangements) for Violin and Piano 10. Carl Maria von Weber, Larghetto, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - To Mischa Elman fritz Kreisler Rondino on a Theme by Beethoven for Violin and Piano, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Ch. De Beriot Werke fur Violine und Klavier Neue Ausgaben in Sorgfaltiger mit Fingersatz Versehener Bearbeitung Op. 77 Erster Fuhrer Des Violins Pielers Suite 2 10 Melodische Etuden, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Premier Guide Du Violoniste 20 Etudes Elementaires pour Violon divisees en 2 Suites par Ch. De Beriot Op. 77 Seconde Partie, undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Erst Sammlung Compositionen Ed Brunner Op. 71 Sonatine in G dur fur zwei und fur Drei Violinen Moszkowski, M. Op. 12 Spanische Tanze tur 2 violine, arr. Von tornauer Heft I, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Jules Hone Morceaux pour Violon avec Accompagnement de Piano Suite Irlandaise (a monsiers M S Foley) 1. When He Who Adores Thee, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and Edited for Violin and Piano 6. Handel Menuett, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and Edited for Violin and Piano 18. C. Ph. E. Bach Menuett, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Fantasie Sur Home Sweet Home pour Violon avec accompagnement de Piano par Jules Hone, undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Jules Hone Morceaux pour Violon avec Accompagnement de Piano Elegie, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Jules Hone Morceaux pour Violon avec Accompagnement de Piano Gavotte, undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Absence pour Violon avec Accompagnement de Piano par Jules Hone, undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 419 Hauser Op. 44 American Rhapsody (Ben Bolt) Violin and Piano, 1906 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Favorite Recital Solos for the Violin with Piano Accompaniment Series 1 A. D'Ambrosio Serenade in D Op. 4, 1904 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters Arranged and Edited for Violin and Piano 8. Handel Arioso, 1906 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - From Mischa Elmans Programme Selected Works of Famous Composers for Violin and Piano Ludwig van Beethoven menuet No. 2 in G, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Inscribed to the Distinguished Violinist Arthur Hardmann An Impression "Appeal d'Amour" (Love's Appeal) for Piano and Violin by Nicola Garagusi, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Willy Burmester Alte Weisen (Old Airs) for Violin and Piano Concert Transcriptions Mendelssohn, Capriccietto, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Aus dem XVIII Jahrfjundert Bearbeitungen fur Violine und Pianoforte von L. Lieberson Fingersatze und Stricharten von Efrem Zimbalist No. 2 Couperin, Fr. (1668-1733) Les papillons, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Jeno Hubay Op. 32 No. 4 Hejre Kati Scene from the Czarda for Violin and Piano, undated (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - As Played by Mischa Elman Gauotte for Violin with Piano Accompaniment, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Le Concert Au Salon Transcriptions de Morceaux Celebres pour Piano and Violon par Vogel and W. Lenz 94. Haendel Airde Rinaldo, undated (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 277 P. Gavinies 24. Studies (matinees) for the Violin (Editied by Emil Kross), 1902 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - fritz Kreisler Original Compositions 2. Caprice Viennois, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Concert and Exhibition Pieces for Violin and Piano Jeno Hubay Op. 30 No. 5 Der Zephyr (Zefir) Revised and Fingered by Ludwig Tadema, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Sarasate, Pablo De Op. 20 Zigeunerweisen (Gypsy Airs), 1895 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Compositions for Violin and Pianoforte Second Series Hauser, M Chanson de Berceau (Cradel Song), undated (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Original Compositions and Arrangements for Violin with Piano Accompaniment Second Series F. Rehfeld Op. 58 No. 1 Spanischer Tanz (Spanish Dances), undated (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Dvorak-Kreisler 3. Slavonic Dances G Minor No. 1 Slavische Tanzweisen (G moll, No. 1), 1914 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Trios for Two Violins and Piano Arranged by G. Vitale, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Musical Score Manuscripts, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 60 Etudes de Concert Concert Studies (Ecole transcendante) pour Violin par for Violin by Ch. De Bariot Op 123 fingered and edited by Hans Wessely, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - C. Fischer's Edition No. 175 Fiorillo 36. Etudes or Caprices Violin (Emil Kross), 1900 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Eduard Keller and Otto K. Schill School of Virtuosity 275 Studies for the Violin for the Development of Technique to Artistic Perfection, with Especial Reference to the playing ofdouble-stops, 1902 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - P. Gavinies 24 Studies Revised in Accordance with thetechnical requirements of modern violin playing and provided with systematic fingering, bowing, dynamic indication and explanatory notes by Emil Kross English translation by Gustav Saenger, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - High School for the Violin by Emil Sauret Op. 36 Part 2 14th Edition, thoroughly revised and greatly enlarged with English, french and German words, 1912 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 101 F Mazas Op. 36 Seventy-Five Melodious and Progressive Studies Book 2 Brilliant Studies Violin, 1901 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - High School for the Violin by Emil Sauret Op. 36 Part 1 14th Edition, thoroughly revised and greatly enlarged with English, french and German words, 1912 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Breitkopf and Hartel's Violin-Bibliothek Breitkopf and Hartel's Editions Library of Violin Music Kleinere Vortragsstucke, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Eduard Keller and Otto K. Schill School of Virtuosity 275 Studies for the Violin for the Development of Technique to Artistic Perfection, with especial reference to the playing of Double-Stops Book 5 Studies No. 201-275, 1902 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Nouvelle Ecole du Violon No. 8 Barcarolle de F. Schubert Transcriptions Violon et Piano par Eduard Remenyi, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - 24 Etudes Classiques pour violon par H Leonard op. 21 Complet, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Empfehlenswerthe Wohlfeile Bandausgaben fur Violine, Viola und Flote 1551 Hauser, M. Op. 8 u. 33 Zwolf Concert-Etuden fur Violine, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - O. Sevcik Op. 2 School of Bowing 4000 Systematic and Progressivly Graded Technical Bowing Exercises Book 2, 1904 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Seinem Lehrer H. Leonard in daukbarer Erinnerung gewiduret 25 Studien fur Violine conponirt von Henry Schradieck Op. 1 Heft 1, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Edition Schott S-9303 H. Leonard Gymnastique Ubungen Auf der Violine La Gymnastique du Violiniste Komplett Kross, 1911 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - A Monsieur Le Prince de Chimay 24 Caprices enforme d'Etudes pour le Violon dans les 24 tons de la Gamme P. Rode Op. 22 Accompt. De 2d Violon ajoute par L. M. Meerts, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 33 etudes de J. B. Cramer pour Violon seul mises en ordre Systematique avec des observations instructives par Louis Abel Propriete de l'Editeur pour tous pays, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Dur und Moll. 25 Etuden, Capricen und Charakterstucke in allen Tonarten zur hohern Ausbildung in Tachnik und Vortrag fur Violine allein von Ferd. David. Op. 39 Neue korrekte Ausgabe von Waldemar Meyer 2 Heft., undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Denni studia Tagliche Studien fur die Violine Florian Lajic, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Dur und Moll. 25 Etuden, Capricen und Charakterstucke in allen Tonarten zur hohern Ausbildung in Tachnik und Vortrag fur Violine allein von Ferd. David. Op. 39 Neue korrekte Ausgabe von Waldemar Meyer 1 Heft., undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - 60 Etudes de Concert Concert Studies (Ecole transcendante) pour Violin par for Violin by Ch. De Bariot Op 123, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Seinem Lehrer H. Leonard in daukbarer Erinnerung gewiduret 25 Studien fur Violine conponirt von Henry Schradieck Op. 1 Heft 2, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 306 Jac. Don't Op. 35 Etudes and Caprices for the Violin, 1903 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Theodore Spiering Sechs Kunstler=Etuden fur die Violine Opus 4 Veri=No. 366, 1908 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - L'Archet Vingt Etudes pour Violon par Paul Viardot, 1898 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - High School for the Violin by Emile Sauret Op. 36 Part 3 14th Edition, thoroughly revised and greatly enlarged with English, French and German words, 1912 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Etudes melodiques et progressives pour le violon compee par F. Mazas Op. 36, 1897 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Violinschute von Joseph Joachim und Andres Moser 2., 1905 (Box 21, Folder 6)